[{"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2ea", "question": "What US state has been led by Theodore and Franklin Roosevelt?", "answer": "New York", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59f9b8dc364247bf200fb884", "question": "Whose debut solo album was titled \"I Got Dem Ol' Kozmic Blues Again Mama!\"?", "answer": "Janis Joplin's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59a1a34a12f2a7826b9b8724", "question": "What was E.T.'s favorite candy?", "answer": "Recee's Pieces", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b5d", "question": "Which Star Wars film introduced the character Lando Calrissian?", "answer": "The Empire Strikes Back", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339124", "question": "Jean de Brunhoff created the appearance of Babar the Elephant, but who invented the character?", "answer": "Cecile de Brunhoff", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dc3", "question": "\"Petunia, No. 2\" was the first of the giant flower canvases painted by what artist?", "answer": "Georgia O'Keeffe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a85e", "question": "Which European country is often referred to as the \"Battlefield of Europe\"?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d50", "question": "Author Margaret Atwood hails from what country?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c982", "question": "By what other name are pink dolphins known?", "answer": "Boto", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a88", "question": "Which comic strip character is the owner of a dog named Otto?", "answer": "Sgt. Snorkel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339745", "question": "What is another name for an Academy Award?", "answer": "Oscar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7d01a877e98cb97778a5b", "question": "Nova Scotia is Latin for what?", "answer": "New Scotland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b1743f2bb2d29f81593b6f7", "question": "How is Barbara Millicent Roberts better known as?", "answer": "Barbie", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea379dff048f679a45ab1b", "question": "What element did Joseph Priestley discover in 1774?", "answer": "Oxygen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2e9", "question": "What is the only insect that can turn its head like humans?", "answer": "Praying mantis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acdc", "question": "What animal is said to have nurtured the founders of Rome, Romulus and Remus?", "answer": "Wolf", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59071cab3745b36be73039ce", "question": "In what present-day country was the first space launch facility located?", "answer": "Kazakhstan", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e9f", "question": "What was the name of Puff the Magic Dragon's homeland?", "answer": "Honalee", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe12e01e39efa6330e0fed1", "question": "Where is the most expensive hotel suite in the U.S.?", "answer": "Las Vegas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c587", "question": "What type of plant is a Saguaro?", "answer": "Cactus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f9c", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Great Expectations\"?", "answer": "Charles Dickens", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4e2", "question": "Which country covers an entire continent?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cae", "question": "What breed of dog is Lassie?", "answer": "Collie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "594a62f72ebb971c1417fb95", "question": "The \"Turbot War\" was a fishing dispute between Spain and what other country?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a76f", "question": "The Brenner Pass lies on the border of Austria and what other country?", "answer": "Italy", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cf2", "question": "In grammar, a complete sentence must include a predicate and a what?", "answer": "Subject", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e13", "question": "What ballet features the famous \"pas de deux\" between the Sugar-Plum Fairy and a cavalier?", "answer": "The Nutcracker", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac36", "question": "By the end of the 20th Century, what war saw the most Americans die?", "answer": "The US Civil War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133892c", "question": "In the novel \"Fahrenheit 451\", what does the title refer to?", "answer": "The temperature at which paper burns", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fefc3fc6ce05a3942286f2a", "question": "What pop duo recorded \"Sweet Dreams (Are Made of This)\"?", "answer": "Eurythmics", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a975", "question": "What nation's legislative body is named The States-General?", "answer": "The Netherlands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fd2", "question": "What TV show did \"The Facts of Life\" spin off from?", "answer": "Diff'rent Strokes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe69e7e20565ad31a57c784", "question": "During World War II, who was Norway's leader and chief Nazi collaborator?", "answer": "Vidkun Quisling", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388d3", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"The Da Vinci Code\"?", "answer": "Dan Brown", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b574", "question": "What are the basic ingredients of beer?", "answer": "Water, Malted Barley, Hops, Yeast", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ec244b8dc25ca9e12ef637", "question": "In which European country would you find the town of Eupen?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c08", "question": "What Ernest Hemingway novel is set during the Spanish Civil War?", "answer": "For Whom the Bell Tolls", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015e7fdfe83fe1f2a824bd8", "question": "Who was the wife of the future Henry VIII\u2019s older brother, Arthur?", "answer": "Catherine of Aragon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aecd", "question": "What US general accepted the surrender of Japan?", "answer": "General Douglas MacArthur", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59c1ceb47bd84c0ea43ad43a", "question": "Who is Thomas John Woodward better known as?", "answer": "Tom Jones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ec2b29543630d44e5be228f", "question": "What is the traditional beverage of Churchill Downs and the Kentucky Derby?", "answer": "Mint Julep", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd9733823c87fd04dd15e57", "question": "How many states were in the original US Confederacy?", "answer": "7", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b03", "question": "Which character killed Elizabeth Vladimir Lensky?", "answer": "Eugene Onegin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5bbd49cd00d154d7af00b8cb", "question": "What year did Nirvana frontman, Kurt Cobain, die?", "answer": "1994", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5f164acef9b80650dbe7f92c", "question": "How many British Admiral-class battlecruisers were cancelled in 1919?", "answer": "Three", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5fa", "question": "The sleeve insignia of a First Class Petty Officer in the US Navy is a spread eagle over how many chevrons?", "answer": "Three", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7bd", "question": "What is measured in Newtons?", "answer": "Force", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59f9bbce364247bf200fb8a8", "question": "Lusaka is the capital of which African country?", "answer": "Zambia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd96c0e23c87fd04dd15e1f", "question": "What U.S. post office doesn't fly the American flag?", "answer": "B. Free Franklin Post Office in Philadelphia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abac", "question": "What is the capital of the state of New York?", "answer": "Albany", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac58", "question": "What year did World War II end?", "answer": "1945", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe769eaeec85e375820b2b4", "question": "Which is the largest of the Spanish Balearic islands?", "answer": "Majorca", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0ae", "question": "Which classic TV show had a theme tune entitled \"Quiz Wizard\"?", "answer": "Blockbusters", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7ae", "question": "What international event is celebrated every April 22nd?", "answer": "Earth Day", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60121c0063c99d48cd169b11", "question": "Where is the oldest African-American theater located in the U.S.?", "answer": "Cleveland, Ohio -- Karamu House opened to the public in 1915. The name is Swahili, meaning \"a place of joyful gathering\".", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58ec24e48dc25ca9e12ef63c", "question": "In Greek Mythology, the Oneiroi, were various gods and demigods that ruled over what?", "answer": "Dreams and nightmares", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339146", "question": "Who created the character Pinocchio?", "answer": "Carlo Collodi", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339be5", "question": "What year did Johnny Depp receive his Hollywood Walk of Fame star in?", "answer": "1999", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c816", "question": "What grape is called Primitivo in Europe?", "answer": "Zinfandel", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7c987877e98cb977789f5", "question": "Which Pennsylvania town is the birthplace of \"Rolling Rock Beer\"?", "answer": "Latrobe", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fc2f17ecee580c7f8fd1e50", "question": "Who said, \"Only the dead have seen the end of war.\"?", "answer": "Plato", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391be", "question": "In which film did Paul Newman play a crime boss named John Rooney?", "answer": "Road to Perdition", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe0de2cfcbed638185eaa13", "question": "What is a \"foss\" in Iceland?", "answer": "A waterfall", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c891", "question": "What does the Richter scale measure?", "answer": "Earthquake magnitude", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a85", "question": "Who flew from England to America in a giant peach carried by seagulls?", "answer": "James", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339220", "question": "Who were the principal members of the band \"The Beatles\"?", "answer": "John Lennon, Paul McCartney, George Harrison, Ringo Starr", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597cdbd1e347d002c297e4e1", "question": "What meteorological significance is traditionally attached to cows lying down?", "answer": "Rain", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff142dfb0ee8c595b6d39af", "question": "In 1905, Pablo Picasso entered his \"Rose Period\", painting jugglers and acrobats from where?", "answer": "Circus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "597cdd69e347d002c297e4f0", "question": "What are affected by Phylloxera?", "answer": "Grapevines", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe76ba9eec85e375820b2c6", "question": "Which ski resort is known as the \"The Queen of the Dolomites\"?", "answer": "Cortina, Italy", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394d4", "question": "What TV sitcom's final episode revealed that the previous seasons had all been a dream?", "answer": "Newhart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b621", "question": "Who designed the Cambridge Z88 computer?", "answer": "Clive Sinclair", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba4c", "question": "What college football championship game has been held in Miami since 1935?", "answer": "Orange Bowl", "category": "general"}, {"id": "592205d4a4edfd43a087adeb", "question": "Of which country did F.W. de Klerk become president in 1989?", "answer": "South Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fede0326ce05a3942286db7", "question": "Which is the only team in NFL history to have scored three touchdowns in less than a minute?", "answer": "New England Patriots", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a4d99c808b8581f80b092b7", "question": "What soccer team won the 2017 FIFA Club World Cup?", "answer": "Real Madrid", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae67", "question": "What nationality was Christopher Columbus?", "answer": "Italian", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa7d", "question": "What is the capital of Azerbaijan?", "answer": "Baku", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4b7", "question": "Who was the first US president to be impeached?", "answer": "Andrew Johnson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a51", "question": "What was the complete name of the toga party band from the movie \"Animal House\"?", "answer": "Otis Day & the Knights", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b819", "question": "What sport has official rules to cover \"tea intervals\"?", "answer": "Cricket", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7f0", "question": "What city, located at the head of the Niagara River, is the seat of New York's Erie County?", "answer": "Buffalo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59071f8a3745b36be73039eb", "question": "The comic book series \"Revival\" is often described as what literary genre?", "answer": "Horror/Rural-noir", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c16b", "question": "In which European city are the headquarters of OPEC?", "answer": "Vienna", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133963f", "question": "In which country was Greta Garbo born?", "answer": "Sweden", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a138", "question": "Who sang the theme song to the film \"The Breakfast Club\"?", "answer": "Simple Minds", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5f95a97e55722f97b22684d0", "question": "What short film featured Mickey Mouse\u2019s first appearance?", "answer": "Plane Crazy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8f2", "question": "A Sone is a unit of what?", "answer": "Loudness", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59636c68967692ea851899aa", "question": "What popular destination helped popularize hot dogs in the US in the 19th century?", "answer": "Coney Island", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133997c", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is Krusty the Clown's real full name?", "answer": "Herschel Shmoikel Pinchas Yerucham Krustofsky", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ef4", "question": "Which literary work's title character is named Bigger Thomas?", "answer": "Native Son", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59008ad4cf842fa4c4ba9693", "question": "What is the name of the lively Spanish dance in triple time and typically performed with castanets or tambourines?", "answer": "Fandango", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a36d", "question": "What soup is likely to be on the menu in Poland or Russia?", "answer": "Borscht", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be04", "question": "What position was first held by Steve Allen?", "answer": "Tonight Show host", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b6991e1e762b54eb9be941e", "question": "What famous statue was discovered in 1820 on the Greek island of Milos?", "answer": "Venus de Milo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59f9b818364247bf200fb87b", "question": "Which game was the first to require installation of the Steam client to play?", "answer": "Half-Life 2", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea7b1bff048f679a45abf2", "question": "Where are carpal bones found?", "answer": "Wrist", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba74", "question": "What NHL team won the Stanley Cup six times during the 1970\u2019s?", "answer": "Montreal Canadiens", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4c3", "question": "Who succeeded Indira Gandhi as Prime Minister of India following her assassination in 1984?", "answer": "Rajiv Gandhi", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58d1180d4fea7fe947a22280", "question": "What is the chemical symbol for lead?", "answer": "Pb", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd5d", "question": "What's the traditional meat on a Reuben sandwich?", "answer": "Corned beef", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d49", "question": "What actress shaved her head for her role in the movie \"Tank Girl\"?", "answer": "Lori Petty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391aa", "question": "Who played James Bond in the 1971 film \"Diamonds Are Forever\"?", "answer": "Sean Connery", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133971e", "question": "In the classic movie \"Animal House\", what was the name of the college?", "answer": "Faber College", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ccf7944b37b32637bdc44bd", "question": "Who was Cesare Borgia's father?", "answer": "Pope Alexander VI", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921e", "question": "What does the \"L\" stand for in Samuel L. Jackson?", "answer": "Leroy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6aa2420565ad31a57c811", "question": "Who became the vice president after Spiro T. Agnew resigned?", "answer": "Gerald Ford", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd2d2532596a59cbdfbd38d", "question": "Who was the only president to also have been Speaker of the House?", "answer": "James K. Polk", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5d6", "question": "Which popular candy bar is named after the maker's favorite horse?", "answer": "Snickers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5eb", "question": "What type of garment are \"Elephant bells\"?", "answer": "Pants", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ab14fabaab681b09292179", "question": "Which Formula One world champion assisted Honda in the final design stages of the NSX?", "answer": "Ayrton Senna", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b4c8749076251badbead6", "question": "What was the first country to put a woman in space?", "answer": "The Soviet Union -- In 1963, cosmonaut Valentina Tereshkova\u00a0orbited the Earth 48 times in a space capsule named Vostok 6.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394b3", "question": "What city did the Solomons call home in the TV show \"3rd Rock from the Sun\"?", "answer": "Rutherford, Ohio", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a312", "question": "\"Video Killed the Radio Star\" was the debut music video on which channel in 1981?", "answer": "MTV", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133931d", "question": "In the movie \"This is Spinal Tap\", what volume does the amplifier go up to?", "answer": "Eleven", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c893", "question": "What does the Schmidt index measure?", "answer": "Pain of insect stings", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afae", "question": "What first ran from Paddington to Farringdon Street in 1863?", "answer": "The London Underground", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59a1a41012f2a7826b9b872c", "question": "Which detective lived in Cabot Cove, Maine?", "answer": "Jessica Fletcher", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a30b", "question": "What character did Pamela Adlon play on the TV show \"Californication\"?", "answer": "Marcy Runkle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe76b51eec85e375820b2c0", "question": "Which is Spain\u2019s oldest, continually inhabited city?", "answer": "C\u00e1diz", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c25", "question": "Who wrote the book \"One Fish, Two Fish, Red Fish, Blue Fish\"?", "answer": "Dr. Seuss", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b298", "question": "Who was the oldest signer of the US Declaration of Independence?", "answer": "Benjamin Franklin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fef5bef6ce05a3942286e1b", "question": "Who directed the film \"Hacksaw Ridge\"?", "answer": "Mel Gibson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c110", "question": "What is the main ingredient of Tapenade?\u00a0", "answer": "Olives", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a4a94b161d1b4d384d5d670", "question": "What is Dana Elaine Owens' stage name?", "answer": "Queen Latifah", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339973", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what IQ does Comic Book Guy posses?", "answer": "170", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe37af80ada16518afdc05e", "question": "What action did the U.S. take along with Great Britain and Australia after Japan seized Indochina?", "answer": "They formed a trade embargo that cut off 90% of Japan's oil supply", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a3f", "question": "What was the last name of Bill Murray\u2019s character\u2019s platoon Sergeant in the movie \"Stripes\"?", "answer": "Hulka", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ae8654e7f28483af1e7fdd0", "question": "What 2015 film broke over 40 box office records upon release?", "answer": "Star Wars: The Force Awakens", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff7c26d2b316f4693fb67a0", "question": "How many steps does the Empire State Building have?", "answer": "1,860", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4ebd406d333868d34d75f", "question": "To whom was the first .com internet domain registered?", "answer": "Symbolics.com", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fecc26cec223966ae8f8875", "question": "What was the first American prime-time network TV drama since the 1970s to star a Black woman as the lead\u202fcharacter?", "answer": "\"Scandal\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60077f15bd51d85e222ab63b", "question": "In biology, a relationship between individuals of two species in which one species obtains food or other benefits from the other without either harming or benefiting the latter is called what?", "answer": "Commensalism", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd66c5da5bfecdd737e0893", "question": "What was the name of the world\u2019s last passenger pigeon?", "answer": "Martha", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ad", "question": "What nationality was Pablo Picasso?", "answer": "Spanish", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7bd50877e98cb97778959", "question": "What continent is located at Latitude 90\u00b0 S Longitude 0.00\u00b0 E?", "answer": "Antarctica", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6016008ffe83fe1f2a824c55", "question": "Who took the very first photograph in the world?", "answer": "Nic\u00e9phore Ni\u00e9pce took the first known photograph, \"View from the Window at Le Gras\", between 1826 and 1827.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8b27201dd7bf43be5e79d", "question": "What does a \"cusp\" birthday imply about your zodiac?", "answer": "Born between two signs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1a9", "question": "What is a \"rosti\"?\u00a0", "answer": "A pancake of fried grated potatoes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fde", "question": "What 1959 Dave Brubeck Quartet piece borrows its name from its unusual time signature?", "answer": "Take Five", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac77", "question": "When was the modern tire first introduced to the market?", "answer": "1887", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe4e19a06d333868d34d728", "question": "How long was Francisco Franco in power in Spain?", "answer": "36 years", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd668bba5bfecdd737e0872", "question": "Which religion has the most gods?", "answer": "Hinduism", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab17", "question": "Where's the famed Arch of Hadrian?", "answer": "Athens", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4d1", "question": "Which two numbers are used in the binary system?", "answer": "Zero and one", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf1e", "question": "What key is to the right of T on a standard keyboard?", "answer": "Y", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b97f", "question": "What is the official residence of the president of France?", "answer": "Elysee Palace", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd6a6b66c0f9723ab15cb56", "question": "Which US state banned alcohol from 1907 until 1966?", "answer": "Mississippi", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a776", "question": "What was the nation of Thailand known as prior to 1949?", "answer": "Siam", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe6a44020565ad31a57c7ba", "question": "The first U.S. transcontinental airmail service connected New York with which city?", "answer": "San Francisco", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c59b", "question": "What is the granular substance that bees collect called?", "answer": "Pollen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fffa8fa73838c5c8a417f40", "question": "What metal has excellent antimicrobial properties?", "answer": "Copper (Ancient Chinese people knew this and used to prescribe copper coins to treat certain diseases.)", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59068111ff9c0647b50a8091", "question": "Before disbanding in 2016, who was the vocalist for the band \"Gossip\"?", "answer": "Beth Ditto", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133922a", "question": "What Welsh songstress has performed the themes for three different Bond movies?", "answer": "Shirley Bassey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cb0", "question": "What breed of dog is Santa's Little Helper?", "answer": "Greyhound", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bda8", "question": "What team's fans were inspired by the Rally Monkey?", "answer": "The Anaheim Angels", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339529", "question": "Who won an Academy Award for her role as Lisa Rowe in the 1999 movie \"Girl, Interrupted\"?", "answer": "Angelina Jolie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7cfbe877e98cb97778a53", "question": "Miami, Florida sits on the bank of what bay?", "answer": "Biscayne Bay", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb98", "question": "What athletic apparel company took its name from the Greek goddess of Victory?", "answer": "Nike", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a87a", "question": "In what city would you find the most famous street named \"La Rambla\"?", "answer": "Barcelona", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59523ef3736d4be723796b55", "question": "What type of interchange, that is widely used in North America and in some parts of Europe, did the Ontario Ministry of Transportation invent?", "answer": "Partial cloverleaf interchange, or Parclo", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe4e8a806d333868d34d74c", "question": "Where can you find Pont Du Gard, part of an ancient Roman aqueduct?", "answer": "N\u00eemes, France", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c9a", "question": "In \"The Hunchback of Notre Dame\", what is the name of the gypsy girl who befriends Quasimodo?", "answer": "Esmeralda", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5990f4d9fa5fdd6dd25324e7", "question": "Central African Republic shares its western border with which country?", "answer": "Cameroon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339903", "question": "What was the name of the decapitated horse in \"The Godfather\"?", "answer": "Khartoum", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5be580ed5415ba52ed6f0abb", "question": "Canada's Maple Leaf national flag was introduced under which Canadian Prime Minister?", "answer": "Lester B. Pearson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f9a", "question": "What character from a pop song wears a screwed-down hairdo and snow-white tan?", "answer": "Ziggy Stardust", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389a0", "question": "What Russian-born sci-fi legend was afraid of flying and heights despite having published numerous books about space?", "answer": "Isaac Asimov", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5feddc5e6ce05a3942286d9b", "question": "Which film included the real 1946 Macy\u2019s Thanksgiving Day Parade?", "answer": "\"Miracle on 34th Street\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339643", "question": "What are the names of the male and female archenemies of Rocky and Bullwinkle?", "answer": "Boris and Natasha", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c12a", "question": "What US city is associated with Alcatraz?", "answer": "San Francisco", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffa3f72c73aa70ea0b70b00", "question": "\"Oro y Plata\" (Gold and Silver) is the motto for which U.S. state?", "answer": "Montana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b23aed98f1a2238a7cb2b3e", "question": "What two countries noticed that they had the same flag at the 1936 Olympics in Berlin?", "answer": "Haiti and Liechtenstein", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59636e3e967692ea851899b2", "question": "What band released their 10th studio album under the name \"Back to Us\"?", "answer": "Rascal Flatts'", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e4", "question": "Which popular musician co-wrote the song \"I'm afraid of Americans\" with David Bowie?", "answer": "Brian Eno", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c619", "question": "What is the chemical symbol for Gold?", "answer": "Au", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe6a98120565ad31a57c805", "question": "Who founded the University of Virginia?", "answer": "Thomas Jefferson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7df", "question": "What are the bumps on the tongue that carry the taste buds called?", "answer": "Papillae", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5feddc4a6ce05a3942286d9a", "question": "\"A Charlie Brown Christmas\" greatly influenced the sales of what product?", "answer": "Aluminum Christmas Trees", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1b9", "question": "What country was called the Gold Coast prior to its 1957 independence?", "answer": "Ghana", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f47", "question": "What is the real first name of Tyler Perry's famous character, Madea?", "answer": "Mabe", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d89", "question": "What famous rapper's real name is Shawn Carter?", "answer": "Jay-Z", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c08", "question": "What year was model Anna Nicole Smith born?", "answer": "1967", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe73e1beec85e375820b271", "question": "In which country might you find Shabu Shabu Nabe?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c51f", "question": "Which body joint includes the patella?", "answer": "Knee", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa6a", "question": "What is the International Calling Code for Australia?", "answer": "61", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b70d", "question": "What is the name given to glittery strings hung on Christmas trees?", "answer": "Tinsel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5bbd4c8a00d154d7af00b8d2", "question": "What is the name of Snoop Dogg's 1993 debut album?", "answer": "Doggystyle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5f95b2ca55722f97b22684df", "question": "What color was Obi-Wan Kenobi's Lightsaber?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be57", "question": "What do Americans commonly call Emmental cheese?", "answer": "Swiss cheese", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58bb3355e368446ca7bd6843", "question": "Who is credited with the invention of the Phillips screw design?", "answer": "John P. Thompson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b589", "question": "What does a Turk call \"Turkish Delight\"?", "answer": "Lokum", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7a9", "question": "What color appears in the middle of a rainbow?", "answer": "Green", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4d9", "question": "How many US states are named after a president?", "answer": "One - Washington", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb4b", "question": "What was the first brand of toothpaste to be sold in tubes rather than jars?", "answer": "Colgate", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febb4697e83c707845b2119", "question": "\"Chicken of the Woods\" is a type of what?", "answer": "Mushroom", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd66cb9a5bfecdd737e0897", "question": "February is named after a Latin word meaning what?", "answer": "Purification", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdc0e44469bb8041d07a05d", "question": "What candy company bought the Friendly's Restaurant chain in 1979?", "answer": "Hershey's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c51e", "question": "What was the name of the first space-ready shuttle?", "answer": "Columbia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c024", "question": "What is the fear of riding in vehicles known as?", "answer": "Ochophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acae", "question": "What date in 1929 saw the shooting of seven members of Bugs Moran's gang in Chicago?", "answer": "February 14", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a97", "question": "In the novel by Jules Verne, who made it around the world in 80 days?", "answer": "Phileas Fogg", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b49", "question": "Who played Al Borland on the TV show \"Home Improvement\"?", "answer": "Richard Karn", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff7bc0b2b316f4693fb678a", "question": "What is a wainwright?", "answer": "A wainwright, also known as cartwright, is someone who repairs wagons and carts.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339be0", "question": "What popular singer had a chimpanzee name Scatter?", "answer": "Elvis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600f742fa9e54d890926f6f4", "question": "What country has competitive office chair racing?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba97", "question": "Before switching to the Euro, what was the monetary unit of Italy?", "answer": "Lira", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133889e", "question": "What was Pinocchio's father's name?", "answer": "Geppetto", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600f71b9a9e54d890926f6e4", "question": "In which Texas city will you find the famous Alamo?", "answer": "San Antonio -- The old mission was the site of a doomed battle in Texas\u2019s war for independence from Mexico.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a69d", "question": "The Shenandoah Valley is located in which eastern US state?", "answer": "Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393d4", "question": "What TV character's first spoken words were \"Goodbye kids\"?", "answer": "Clarabell the Clown", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a605", "question": "Vienna and Belgrade lie on the banks of which river?", "answer": "The Danube", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c538", "question": "What is the only planet in the solar system that is named after a female figure?", "answer": "Venus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea8025ff048f679a45ac18", "question": "What period did the Tyrannosaurus Rex live during?", "answer": "Cretaceous", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a026", "question": "Which \"Family Guy\" character is paralyzed from the waist down?", "answer": "Joe Swanson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7a7", "question": "Of the seven colors of the rainbow which is the middle one?", "answer": "Green", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a72f", "question": "The Simi Valley is located in which US state?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7c766877e98cb977789cd", "question": "Where is Bohemian Switzerland National Park?", "answer": "Czech Republic", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392f2", "question": "In the movie \"Saving Private Ryan\", how many of the Ryan brothers were soldiers?", "answer": "Four", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a7dc20565ad31a57c7f0", "question": "What was the first slogan for OREO cookies?", "answer": "Oh! Oh! Oreo!", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be4b", "question": "What two pins are left standing in bowling's hardest split to pick up?", "answer": "The 7 and 10", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4de", "question": "What fruit comes in Hass and Florida variety?", "answer": "Avocados", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f61", "question": "According to Dustin Hoffman in \"Rain Man\", what's the only airline that has never had a crash?", "answer": "Qantas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59e6b627fb6c85e9e634ff47", "question": "Androphobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Males, or men", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c135", "question": "Which significant beverage did John Pemberton invent in 1886?", "answer": "Coca-Cola", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a712", "question": "Which US state is home to Lake Havasu City?", "answer": "Arizona", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c13c", "question": "With which instrument is jazz musician Charlie Mingus principally associated?", "answer": "Double Bass", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5c62b8ab0ae4aacefc17eee2", "question": "Metallica released what song on the album \"Mission: Impossible 2\"?", "answer": "I Disappear", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390d4", "question": "Who painted the \"Laughing Cavalier\"?", "answer": "Frans Hals", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59db771b0ab2c8f322317feb", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", who or what is Santa's Little Helper?", "answer": "The Simpsons' pet dog", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339227", "question": "What decade did Marty McFly go back to in \"Back to the Future\"?", "answer": "1950's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "592206dfa4edfd43a087adf0", "question": "Tips of hair that are damaged are called what?", "answer": "Split ends", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bae3", "question": "First minted in 2000, whose likeness was on the face-side of the US dollar coin?", "answer": "Sacagawea", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5989aee8cb8751d53e7d7618", "question": "What is the largest North American country by land area?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b865", "question": "What is the only bird to be honored by its own year on the Chinese calendar?", "answer": "Rooster", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60136f681381754895396375", "question": "Where is Superman\u2019s Fortress of Solitude?", "answer": "Arctic Circle -- Although he's had different bachelor pads, he classically heads to the Arctic Circle when he wants to be alone.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b551", "question": "What country has the highest consumption of candy annually per person?", "answer": "Denmark", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b675", "question": "What was William Fox Talbot a pioneer of?", "answer": "Photography", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd666faa5bfecdd737e0869", "question": "What is the busiest time of the year for air travel in the U.S.?", "answer": "Thanksgiving", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7c959877e98cb977789f3", "question": "What state is home to a lake known as \"America\u2019s Dead Sea\"?", "answer": "Utah", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f64", "question": "Whose halftime set at Super Bowl XLI was performed during a downpour?", "answer": "Prince's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4fd", "question": "What was the name of the Apollo 11 lunar module?", "answer": "Eagle", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a162cf2f01ec323f8491734", "question": "An astronomical unit is the standard measurement taken from the Earth to where?", "answer": "The Sun", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59ae9485574a5ce6b56b8249", "question": "\"Nobody Does it Better\" was the theme song of which Bond film?", "answer": "The Spy Who Loved Me", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe9f0ecff048f679a45aaab", "question": "Verminophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Germs", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c26e", "question": "What is May's birthstone?", "answer": "Emerald", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcd9", "question": "What was the only place Tandy's popular TRS-80 computers were sold?", "answer": "RadioShack", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea77ccff048f679a45abcf", "question": "What is the name for a female fox?", "answer": "Vixen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58b36f991c3f17ccc40c8e0f", "question": "Who plays the role of Haley Joel Osment\u2019s mother in the film \"The Sixth Sense\"?", "answer": "Toni Collette", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bb357722627b8fe95581be4", "question": "Brisbane is the capital of which Australian state?", "answer": "Queensland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b92a", "question": "What nationality was Dr. James Naismith, the inventor of basketball?", "answer": "Canadian", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399df", "question": "In the 1991 animated Disney film \"Beauty and the Beast\", what type of enchanted item is Chip?", "answer": "A teacup", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b42", "question": "What is the name of Bilbo Baggins' magical sword in \"The Hobbit\"?", "answer": "Sting", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2c9", "question": "Who was the US's first postmaster general?", "answer": "Benjamin Franklin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fecda1bec223966ae8f88e6", "question": "What character in \"Monty Python and the Holy Grail\" insists that \"It's just a flesh wound\"?", "answer": "Black Knight", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef93fe6ce05a3942286e93", "question": "What show did \"TV Guide\" name the \"best TV show of all time\" in 2002?", "answer": "\"Seinfeld\"", "category": "entertainment"}]